lan Matsumoto

DATA SPECIALIST

CONTACT



https://github.com/ianmat55



808-679-7230



ianmat55@gmail.com

PROFILE

Ian Matsumoto is an analyst and aspiring software engineer. Traveling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic.

EDUCATION

University of Redlands

Bachelor of Science (2015-2019)

Environmental Science

GIS

Mathematics

SKILLS

Technologies:

Git

GIS based systems

Languages:

Python

SQL

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Node

Professional:

QA processing

New hire training

Technical writing

Adaptability

Time management

Worflow documentation

WORK HISTORY

Data Annotation Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- Served as a bottleneck of data labeling for six teams,
 identifying areas critical to training the neural network
- labled and verified an average of 100 data sets per day in a dynamic workflow
- Serve as a critical asset to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process. Identify and resolve Quality Assurance workflow issues and improvement initiatives.
- Drive teams to improve processes, explicate data and yield meaningful metrics.
- Direct two daily feedback reports for engineering, project management, and leadership teams.
- Worked in dynamic environment helping with various teams and filling numerous roles under Tesla autopilot

GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems (Contract) | 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps

- Conduct web research on construction projects and track their progress through Apple's GIS software
- Responsible for updated and tracking maps in Riverside,
 San Bernardino, and Orange County
- Monitor traffic and pedestrian density on maps to identify areas of potential construction
- Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials, private companies and peers regarding new projects

PROJECTS

JobScraper.io

technologies | Node, Express, Postgresql, HTML/CSS/EJS

• Webscraper that scrapes linkedin, indeed and google jobs for listings that meet specified criteria. Built using Node/Express framework, ejs front end, and Postgresql database. Jobscraper.io was built to streamline my job searching process and also serve as a portfolio piece.

CLI Websocket Chatbot

technologies | Python, Socket Communication

• In terminal chatroom utilizing socket and tcp communication. The multi-client server class inherits from the base client class, accepting other client connections and relaying data to all users in the room.

Birthday Storage App

technologies | Flask, mySQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript

• Flask CRUD application that stores friend's birthday and and name utilizing SQLite for a lightweight test application.